<table name="project" id="Scope">
    <column name="title">Scope</column>
    <date>2019.4-2019.9</date>
    <link>
        <![CDATA[
            <li>
                <a>Link</a>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <a href="http://u880691907-robingan-org.hostingerapp.com">Website</a>
                    </li>

                    <li>
                        <a href="https://github.com/robingan7/Scope">View Code</a>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </li>
            <li>
                <a>Team</a>
                <ul>
                    
                </ul>
            </li>
            <li>
                <a>Gallery</a>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <a href="https://youtu.be/lCXy4XA_t8Q">Video</a>
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </li>
            ]]>
    </link>
    <content>
        <![CDATA[
            <h3>Intro</h3>
            <p>In this <a href="/media/#Why_do_scouting_apps_matter?">blog</a>, I talk about how scouting works in <a href="https://www.firstinspires.org/robotics/frc">FRC(First Robotics Competition)</a> events and the significance of a working scouting website or app for a team. </p>

            <p>This is the biggest project I worked on in high school, but it's not worthy for the hours and hours of time I spent on it because it didn't turn out to work well but I did learn from the mistake. 
            </p>

            <h4>Why I made this project</h4>
            <p>After I made <a href="/project/#frcscouting.ga">frcscouting.ga</a>, I was interesting in 
                making websites and decided to learn <a href="https://angular.io/">Angular</a> to make the best scouting apps ever for all 
                <a href="https://www.firstinspires.org/robotics/frc">FRC</a> teams. So I hoped that I could make a impact in the community. 
            </p>


            <h3>Challenges</h3>
            <h4>Scouts & Managers Role</h4>
            <p>None of the scouting apps I know have this feature. One of the most convenient features of this website is that it has the Scouts & Managers roles, where the managers can assign tasks to scouts. The managers can also view the progress of each scout. And each team can only have one manager to make the process easier to organize.  
            </p>
            <p><img src="/images/project/Scope/managerandscout.png" alt="managerandscout"/></p>

            <h4>Task section</h4>
            <p>Here are the things the users can do in the task section,</p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <p><strong>Set and change events(manager only):</strong> 
                    the users can set and change the <a href="https://frc-events.firstinspires.org/">FRC events</a> they are currently competing at. 
                By doing this, the website can provide the teams and matches data at that events for enabling convenient features in other sections. Thanks to <a href="https://www.thebluealliance.com/apidocs/v3">thebluealliance api</a>, 
                I was able to access to all the events information.</p> 
                <p><img src="/images/project/Scope/setevent.png" alt="setevent"/></p>

                </li>

                <li>
                    <p><strong>View and start current tasks:</strong> for scout who has tasks assigned to them. They can view and start tasks in this section. </p>
                    <p><img src="/images/project/Scope/matchtasks.png" alt="matchtasks"/></p>
                    <p><img src="/images/project/Scope/pittasks.png" alt="pittasks"/></p>
                </li>

                <li>
                    <p><strong>Created and edit(manager only) form:</strong> the manager can edit pit and match scouting form, which is changing the aspects they want their scout to look for during scouting. They can also edit the customized questions for their team. 
                    </p>
                    <p><img src="/images/project/Scope/editform.png" alt="editform"/></p>
                </li>
            </ul>

            <h4>Manage section(manager only)</h4>
            <p>The manager can add, edit and delete his or her scouts' tasks in this section. </p>
            <p><img src="/images/project/Scope/addtasks.png" alt="addtasks"/></p>
            <p><img src="/images/project/Scope/edittasks.png" alt="edittasks"/></p>
            <p><img src="/images/project/Scope/managermodal.png" alt="managermodal"/></p>

            <h4>History section</h4>
            <p>Under this tab, the users can view and edit all the matches they scout. For the manager, he or she can view and edit all the matches from his or her scouts. 
            </p>
            <p><img src="/images/project/Scope/history.png" alt="history"/></p>
            <p><img src="/images/project/Scope/historypit.png" alt="historypit"/></p>

            <h4>Data section</h4>
            <p>In this section, the users can view and rank teams from the data they scout with 100+ filters. They can also save the team they like for alliance selection. 
            </p>
            <p><img src="/images/project/Scope/data.png" alt="data"/></p>

            <h4>Teamlist section</h4>
            <p>In this section, the users can rank the teams they liked for final adjustment or better decisions in alliance selection. They can also cross off the teams that are already picked. 
            </p>
            <p><img src="/images/project/Scope/teamliked.png" alt="teamliked"/></p>

            <h4>Bluealliance API</h4>
            <p>I used <a href="https://www.thebluealliance.com/apidocs/v3">thebluealliance api</a> a lot for this project. For examples, </p>
            <ul>
                <li><p>In the task section, if the user click "add pit scout", the team numbers in their event will automatically show up. </p>
                <p><img src="/images/project/Scope/api1.png" alt="api1"/></p>
                </li>

                <li>
                    <p>When the managers are adding tasks for the scout, the website can tell them the max qualication match number they can put in for that event. </p>
                    <p><img src="/images/project/Scope/api2.png" alt="api2"/></p>
                </li>

                <li>
                    <p>When the scout open his or her task, the number of the team they need to scout will automatically show up based on the position their manager choose.</p>
                    <p><img src="/images/project/Scope/api3.png" alt="api3"/></p>

                </li>
            </ul>

            
            <h3>Conclusion</h3>
            <h4>Mistake I made</h4>
            <p>After hours and hours of effort, this website's never used. Here are some mistakes that causes this:</p>
            <ul>
                <li><strong>Impossible to update:</strong> when I coded this, I did NOT think about how I will update 
                this website for next year. At the time when I need, I found out how messy the code was and made the website impossible to update to 2020 game.</li>
                <li><strong>Security issue:</strong> I did NOT realize that the passwords needed to be encrypted. So I don't want to let other people use this website.</li>
                <li>I can't code big project like this all by myself. It's not a good idea. </li>
            </ul>
            ]]>
    </content>
</table>